Mr choky what is your understanding of
the partial lockdown and we understand
that a lot of cement companies are
looking at restarting their operations
what is JK LXI planning to do now that
partial lockdown is
lifted well uh we to have started
operations in some of our units like in
Gujarat chtis gar we have already
resumed in Rajasthan we are expecting
that we'll be starting things today both
at udur and Siri
so that uh takes care of almost about 80
80% of our capacity should resume
partial operation uh harana is the only
place which still uh seems a bit away
but rest of the places we are starting
the partial uh operations from
today when you say partial operations uh
how much your current capacity would be
let's say on stream by this
week uh we expect we'll be doing about
30 35% of our capacity you see the
challenge is not the operations today
there are two basic challenges one is
the supply chain for the logistic and
the trucks Etc to get back on the system
so while we have taken all the care for
social distancing hygiene sanitation
fumigation all that is in place
but the issue is number one getting the
trucks back into the cycle that is uh
the challenges to get to the the drivers
to the the truck Lot number of trucks
are still
standard number two the biggest issue is
I think the the
demand creation because the most of the
construction sites today do not have the
labor and the labor especially the
Immigrant labor which consisted of lot
many of these construction workers daily
wage earners uh till the time they are
able to come back the full operation
will still be you know some some time
away but having said that uh most of the
construction in the rural areas we find
will get resumed for two reasons some of
one the they are able to make do with
the local labor number two is the most
of the state governments especially the
central government is very keen that you
know the economic cycle get back on on
track and therefore construction is one
of the activity which kick starts the
economy rather quickly so I think uh all
the variables are in place to ensure
that you know these things get moving so
while reaching to the peak capacity
would obviously take some time it's a
huge challenge but I think uh not All Is
Lost we we should should be reaching
about 50% capacity utilization by June
end that's what we
believe sure okay so June end is what
you're looking at um how are you
preparing for that as well in terms of
precautionary measures uh in terms of
you know in terms of really how uh
you'll you'll sort of have your daily
weage laborers also coming in on this uh
those that need to come back into
certain areas resuming work uh
precautionary measures again even for
them uh getting back in touch with
dealers who who've also been completely
shut down during this
time yeah sure you see we have a very
detailed standard operating procedure
laid down uh fortunately in many of our
plants we have workers who are staying
within the colony so they have in a
sense got used to uh observing these
norms for last nearly a month
in fact even before this lockdown
happened we had started from almost the
first week of March so the measures like
the staggered shift timing the screening
of the workers at the factory gate uh
keeping you know working with about 50
to 60% of the workers so we have taken
lot many measures in place uh today we
are practically a paperless uh operation
when when the driver enters and right up
to the point point when he exits so
except for the EV Bill he is not
carrying anything else so I think the
minimum interface of the people people
to people is what we are trying to
attempt and I think we are we are fairly
confident that as far as we are
concerned and the procedures that we
have adopted will not be a problem
coming to the major question of the
demand and the sorry the dealers and the
network how do we really connect with
them I think one of the opportunity that
we have got uh during this period of one
month is we have been practically
interacting with 4,000 5,000 odd dealers
of ours and some good 5 to 800 key
customers of ours with whom we have been
in touch and some of the other person
from our organization has been in touch
with them every day every single day
first to ass certain how they are
keeping sensitizing them that the Norms
to be followed
and again we have worked out a operating
procedure for them when they are working
from their shop or from their Outlets so
I think this opportunity of one month
has been very well utilized to sensitize
all the stakeholders in the entire value
chain Mr choky how has pricing been
disrupted and post the lockdown as well
uh how do you see Trends p planning out
do you see a further reduction in
pricing well a reduction in the pricing
is something I don't think uh the
industry can afford at this time with 30
or 40% of the capacity running and uh
very little Headroom for improving the
efficiencies as uh in many of the areas
Indian human industry is a benchmark
today in the world so there are really
very little scope everyone is trying to
work through cutting down the fix cost
and of course conserving the cash Etc
but the headro really is very less so I
do not see any uh prices really going
down the challenge would be to operate
even at the uh pre-close of prices that
itself will be a huge challenge but we
are grappling with it we are trying to
you know maintain that ensure that the
supply chain costs do not in well that's
another threat that we are facing with a
limited number of trucks and we trying
to resume the operation there's always a
fear that the supply chain cost may go
up similarly the dealers who are who
will be operating with much less number
of uh much less volume would also try to
increase the price to you know to just
even just for a break even so I think we
have challenges all around but we are
quite confident at the same time that
we'll try to overcome them all of them
good fantastic thanks so much for
joining us uh this morning Mr choky good
to hear of the kind of developments
underway there